RUBEN BRIONEZ JR

ASPIRING DATA PROFESSIONAL



813 541 2588







Portfolio

EDUCATION

MASTER'S OF SCIENCE DATA SCIENCE Bellevue University 2024

BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE INFORMATION STUDIES University of South Florida 2014

TECHINCAL SKILLS

R Programming and RStudio

Machine Learning Concepts

R Markdown

Python

Numpy

Pandas

Jupyter Notebooks

Version Control with GitHub

Data Visualization with R

Regression Modeling

API Interaction

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Process Improvement

Team Leadership

Strategic Planning

Critical Thinking

Initiative

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Strategic, innovative, forward-thinking leader setting standards for a regional telecommunications design team. I have gained 10+ years of industry knowledge and experience, and I would now like to transition that knowledge to another field.

I am continuing my education with a master's in data science to further supplement my experience, knowledge, and aid in pivoting to a new role.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

GRADUATE STUDENT

Bellevue University / Omaha, NE (Remote) / 2023 - Present

I enrolled in the Data Science Graduate program at Bellevue University in September of 2023. I'm pursuing my Master's in an effort to continue growing my professional career and expanding my knowledge of Data Science.

- Used R-Programming with RStudio to analyze firearm purchases in Florida over time.
- Utilized the K-means and Nearest neighbor machine learning algorithms in R on a provided dataset.
- Used Python with Jupyter Notebooks for exploratory data analysis of 2006 NSFG data provided by the Center for Disease and Control.
- Used Python with PyCharm IDE to access an OpenWeather API, parse JSON, and report back data based on a user's request.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HFC DESIGNER III

Charter Communications / Riverview, FL / 2018 - Present

As an HFC Designer III, I am the subject matter expert for outside plant for the Florida region. I am the lead in data driven projects and analysis in regard to outside design and construction initiatives.

- Led multiple team-based projects and effectively coordinated group tasks.
- Led address reconciliation project in ArcGIS, utilizing SQL to query tables in a database and update records.
- Spearheaded cross training program, proactively engaging multiple members of the design team to set and create various Florida Design standards.
- Regional SME for design data, processes, and software.

FIBER DESIGNER II

Bright House Communications / Riverview, FL / 2014 - 2018

As a Fiber Designer II, I was responsible for maintaining and updating the company's fiber records. I was also responsible for creating construction blueprints, diagrams and providing instructions to build enterprise fiber connections.

- Helped create and implement company standards for FTTH and FTTX construction.
- Created, updated, and maintained fiber records for six counties in Florida.
- Directly worked with the Construction and Maintenance teams for storm preparation and recovery of vital fiber routes for EMS.